Sk Md Sohel

skmdsohel.vercel.app | Linkedin

Location: Bengaluru, Karnataka, India mdsohel181@gmail.com | Mobile: +918972667203

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced Software Engineer II with 2 years 10 months of experience in software development and programming. Adept at designing, developing and troubleshooting software applications. Proven success in developing integrated technical solutions for past organizations with a strong focus on quality and customer satisfaction.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End : React, Angular, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap, PrimeNG, Material UI

Back-End : ExpressJS, MongoDB

Others : Visual Studio Code, Git, GitHub, Nginx, Docker

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer II

Mar 2023 – Present

Terralogic Inc.

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

- Developed and implemented software solutions to improve system efficiency and streamline operations, resulting in a 15% increase in productivity.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to gather requirements, design, and develop scalable applications, ensuring seamless integration of new features and functionalities.
- Conducted thorough code reviews and implemented best practices to ensure code quality and adherence to industry standards, resulting in a reduction of system bugs by 30%.

Engineer Jan 2021 – Mar 2023

L&T Technology Services Ltd.

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

- Conducted thorough root cause analysis and implemented corrective actions, reducing application downtime by 30% and improving overall reliability.
- Responsible for implementing responsive user interfaces, integrating APIs, handling data binding, and ensuring a smooth user experience.
- Developed and implemented efficient engineering solutions to optimize production processes, resulting in a 20% increase in overall productivity.

Engineering Intern Sep 2020 – Dec 2020

L&T Technology Services Ltd. Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

• Assisted in the design and testing of new prototypes, ensuring adherence to industry standards and regulations.

EDUCATION

VIT University

M.Tech in Computer Science

Vellore, Tamil Nadu, India Jul 2018 – Jun 2020

PROJECTS

Personal Portfolio web app

ReactJS, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

Here, I showcase my expertise and skills. Through an elegant and minimalist design.

FoodStore

ReactJS, Redux-toolkit, tailwind CSS

• FoodStore application is a convenient and user-friendly platform that allows customers to browse food from various restaurants and add it to Cart show total value of the cart

CERTIFICATIONS

- The Complete 2023 Web Development Bootcamp
- · Certificate on JavaScript by Hackerrank
- · Certificate on Problem Solving by Hackerrank